<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>3r1c.net</title>
    <link>http://3r1c.net</link>
    <description>A text-based, RSS focused blogging system</description>
    <copyright></copyright>
    <ttl>60</ttl>
<item>
<pubDate>2023-11-18T11:24:56Z 13:31:19 CET</pubDate>
  <category>2023/11/18/6</category>
  <title>FIRST MAJOR PATCH AND QOL IMPROVEMENTS</title>
  <link>http://3r1c.net/posts/patch-1.txt</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[
<pre style='border: 0; white-space: pre-wrap; word-break: break-word;'>The main shinobi script has received its first external patch!

It&#39;s getting just past 10PM on this stormy Sunday night, but I have an 
urge to share this post now instead of waiting for next week. 
Afterwards I&#39;ll be going to bed before the start of a new week.

If you&#39;ve been following along, you might have noticed a pretty solid 
patch has been added to the core shinobi script project:

https://git.sr.ht/~tdarb/shinobi-script

Special shout out to Matthew Graybosch[0] for putting together these 
improvements and working towards a more consistent experience across 
all RSS readers.


THE CHANGES AT A GLANCE
-----------------------

In a nutshell:

- text inside the CDATA tag is now wrapped with &lt;pre&gt; tags
- &lt;pre&gt; tag has inline CSS to specify reasonable wrapping
- tail command to retrieve post text now pipes into sed to escape HTML 
tags.
- added test posts
- added makefile for local testing

Please take a look at the changes directly in the official patch 
notes[1]. Take notice of some of the new folders/files included with 
the default project. You&#39;ll also see updated instructions in the README 
to help with testing and local development.


QUALITY OF LIFE
---------------

In addition to the first major patch, I&#39;ve included basic styling to 
properly render the RSS feed directory in supported browsers. To see it 
in action, simply check out:

https://shinobi.website/feed.xml

The styles are included in the new `rss.css` file of the shinobi 
project. The current layout is taken from Len Falken&#39;s main 
directory[2]. Feel free to change this to however you see fit! I&#39;ve 
kept them consistent with the remainder of the project, but there is 
nothing stopping you from including things like XSLT.

To reflect these changes, I&#39;ve updated some of the details found in the 
original &quot;SIMPLE GUIDE FOR CREATING YOUR OWN SHINOBI.WEBSITE&quot;[3]


TESTING, TESTING, TESTING
-------------------------

I&#39;m trying my best to test every RSS reader available to me. My main 
machine is running macOS and my phone iOS, thus making me somewhat 
limited in my access to other OS-specific RSS applications. Even still, 
I&#39;ve added a growing list to the project README documenting readers 
that have been tested, along with their support &quot;grade&quot;. Feel free to 
include your own testing in tickets or patches on your own!

That is really all there is to say. Enjoy your week!


LINKS
-----

[0]: https://matthewgraybosch.com
[1]: 
https://git.sr.ht/~tdarb/shinobi-script/log?from=7e2f8bd312d648ff1c8d3cf
dc747d2e5634100d7#log-7e2f8bd312d648ff1c8d3cfdc747d2e5634100d7
[2]: http://len.falken.directory
[3]: https://shinobi.website/posts/create-your-own-shinobi-website.txt


***

Thanks for reading,
-- Brad</pre>]]>
  </description>
  <author>3r1c</author>
  <guid>http://3r1c.net/posts/patch-1.txt</guid>
  </item>
<item>
<pubDate>2023-11-18T11:24:56Z 13:31:19 CET</pubDate>
  <category>2023/11/18/6</category>
  <title>titre</title>
  <link>http://3r1c.net/posts/test.txt</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[
<pre style='border: 0; white-space: pre-wrap; word-break: break-word;'>ddd ca va ?</pre>]]>
  </description>
  <author>3r1c</author>
  <guid>http://3r1c.net/posts/test.txt</guid>
  </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
